Guide to the Adolph M. Foerster Collection, 1868-1923 CAM.FOER.2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Music Manuscripts, I.
  - Opus 34 no. 1 I saw thee weep, November 1, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    Holograph score. The front leaf has the complete title, dedication, and publisher's information and was probably the copy sent to the printer.
  - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 67, Item 67a)
    Leaf 2 has note in Foerster's hand "Two themes from songs op. 34. See supplement.": Rest copied by Gus Mueller: Bound in linen cover.
  - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron (Box 5, Folder 68)
    Score manuscript and parts. bound in leather cover.: copied by Gus Mueller, no date: slightly different from 67A.
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: score (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68a)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st violin (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68b)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 2nd violin (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68c)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: viola (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68d)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: cello (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68e)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: bass (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68f)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st flute (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68g)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 2nd flute (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68h)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st oboe (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68i)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 2nd oboe (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68j)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st clarinet (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68k)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 2nd clarinet (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68l)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st bassoon (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68m)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 2nd bassoon (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68n)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st and 2nd horn (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68o)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 3rd and 4th horn (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68p)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st trumpet (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68q)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 2nd trumpet (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68r)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 1st trombone (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68s)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 2nd trombone (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68t)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: 3rd trombone (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68u)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: tuba (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68v)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: tympani (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68w)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: snare drum (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68x)
    - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron: bass drum (Box 5, Folder 68, Item 68y)
  - Opus 35 Symphonic ode to Byron, October 24, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    Holograph score. early piano score with some indications as to orchestration. At the end is the above date and "Robert Franz died."
  - Opus 38 no. 9 Antique (Box 5, Folder 72)
    Holograph score.
  - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion (Box 5, Folder 74)
    Holograph manuscript. Title is Devotion but later scores call it Cavatina.
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion: score (Box 5, Folder 74, Item 74a)
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion: cello (Box 5, Folder 74, Item 74b)
  - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion (Box 5, Folder 75)
    Holograph score. Marked as revised copy. Part also includes No. 2
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion: score (Box 5, Folder 75, Item 75a)
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion: cello (Box 5, Folder 75, Item 75b)
  - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Cavatina (Box 5, Folder 76)
    Holograph score. still not the final version. Many changes in score.
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Cavatina: score (Box 5, Folder 76, Item 75a)
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Cavatina: cello (Box 5, Folder 76, Item 75b)
  - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Cavatina (Box 5, Folder 77)
    same as published.: retitled "Devotion"
  - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion (Box 5, Folder 78)
    score holograph and part. bound with 78c with gamble hinge.
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion: score (Box 5, Folder 78, Item 78a)
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 1 Devotion: cello (Box 5, Folder 78, Item 78b)
    - Opus 39 Two pieces for violoncello and piano No. 2 Cavatina (Box 5, Folder 78, Item 78c)
  - Opus 39 Cavatina (no 2) (Box 5, Folder 80)
    Holograph score. This is marked as no. 1 but is really no. 2. Since the copyright date is 1922 it is no doubt an attempt by the composer to fill in the gaps in his complete works, thus accounting for the inconsistencies.
    - Opus 39 Cavatina (no 2): score (Box 5, Folder 80, Item 80a)
    - Opus 39 Cavatina (no 2): cello (Box 5, Folder 80, Item 80b)
  - Opus 39 No. 1 Devotion (Box 5, Folder 81)
    Holograph score and parts. Last leaf only.
    - Opus 39 No. 1 Devotion (Box 5, Folder 81, Item 81a)
    - Opus 39 No. 1 Devotion (Box 5, Folder 81, Item 81b)
  - Opus 40 Second piano quartet, January 1895 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    Holograph score. 38 pages. second leaf has listed the first two performances and players. Bound with heavy board cover.
  - Opus 40 Second piano quartet, January 1895 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    Holograph score. 57 pages. First leaf has date, place and performers of first performance. Bound with linen cover and gamble hinge.
  - Opus 40 Second piano quartet (Box 5, Folder 84)
    Score manuscript and parts. 45 pages. revised copy, bound with heavy board cover. First leaf has list of first two performances and clippings from program and newspaper giving players.
    - Opus 40 Second piano quartet: score (Box 5, Folder 84, Item 84a)
    - Opus 40 Second piano quartet: violin (Box 5, Folder 84, Item 84b)
    - Opus 40 Second piano quartet: viola (Box 5, Folder 84, Item 84c)
    - Opus 40 Second piano quartet: cello (Box 5, Folder 84, Item 84d)
  - Opus 41 Second string quartet, September 1894 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    Holograph score. first movement
    - Opus 41 Second string quartet: score, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 85, Item 85a)
    - Opus 41 Second string quartet: cello, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 85, Item 85b)
  - Opus 42 no. 1 Autumn leaves, April 1894 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    Holograph score. Voice and piano.
  - Opus 43 Dedication march, October 1895 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    Holograph orchestra manuscript and parts.
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st violin, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89a)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd violin, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89b)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: viola, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89c)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: cello, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89d)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: bass, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89e)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: tenor sax, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89f)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: alto sax, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89g)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd clarinet, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89g)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st clarinet, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89i)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: Casso-Piotti, 1895 (Box 7, Item 89j)
  - Opus 44 Hero and Leander, May 28, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    Holograph score. Voice and piano. AT the bottom of page 10 and across page 11 are 15 measures to be inserted at the bottom of page 8. This addition appears in all later copies.
  - Opus 44 Hero and Leander, July 27, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 94)
    Holograph manuscript. 8 pages. This version gives it its final form with a few more changes.
  - Opus 44 Hero and Leander, May 28, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 95)
    Holograph manuscript. 13 pages.
  - Opus 44 Hero and Leander, May 28, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 96)
    Holograph manuscript. 11 pages.
  - Opus 44 Hero and Leander, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 97)
    Holograph manuscript. Soprano and orchestra. 27 pages.
  - Opus 44 Hero and Leander, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 98)
    Holograph score and parts.
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: score, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98a)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st violin, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98b)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 2nd violin, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98c)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: viola, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98d)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: cello, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98e)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: bass, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98f)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st and 2nd flute, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98g)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st and 2nd oboe, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98h)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st and 2nd clarinet, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98i)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st and 2nd bassoon, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98j)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st and 2nd horn, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98k)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 3rd and 4th horn, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98l)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st and 2nd trombone, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98m)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 3rd trombone, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98n)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: 1st and 2nd trumpet, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98o)
    - Opus 44 Hero and Leander: tympani, July 4, 1897 (Box 7, Item 98p)
  - Opus 45 no. 1 The Grecian isles, May 17, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 99)
    Holograph score. last thirty measures only.
  - Opus 46 no. 3 Waltz (Box 7, Folder 104)
    Holograph score. Pencil sketch of about 43 measures from the middle. Beginning and ending missing.
  - Opus 47 Second Suite (Box 7, Folder 105)
    Holograph score. Probably the first sketch as many sections can be identified with the proof copy.
  - Opus 47 no. 3 Reverie, November 7, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    Holograph score. Early sketch, pages 1 & 4 in pencil; pages 2 & 3 in ink.
  - Opus 45 no. 5 Festivity, October 25, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    Holograph score. Pencil sketch.
  - Opus 47 Scherzo-waltz from suite no. 2 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    Holograph score. This movement consists of about 200 measures but does not appear in other MS or published form.
  - Opus 47 Scherzo-waltz from suite no. 2, March 1, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    Holograph score. Pencil score of a movement not included in the suite. The first 10 pages are in 3/4 time, pages 11 and 12 are blank and pages 13 through 43 are in 4/4 time, a total of 421 measures. This movement was probably discarded in favor of the one in the published version.: p. 12 blank
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust, March 21, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 111)
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust (Box 7, Folder 112)
    Holograph score. Many corrections in Foerster's handwriting. Last page is missing, about 8 measures.
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust (Box 7, Folder 113)
    Orchestra manuscript. Many corrections. 40 pages.
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust (Box 7, Folder 114)
    Holograph manuscript. 30 pages. Heavy paper cover, loose pages.: Includes front and Back of page fragment found in score
  - Opus 50 Sigrid, symphonic poem for orchestra (Box 7, Folder 119)
    Holograph score. pencil sketch, probably the first.
  - Opus 50 Sigrid, symphonic poem for orchestra, October 18, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 120)
    Holograph score. Incomplete, pencil sketch
  - Opus 50 Sigrid, symphonic poem for orchestra (Box 7, Folder 121)
    Holograph score. Incomplete
  - Opus 50 Sigrid, symphonic poem for orchestra (Box 7, Folder 122)
    Holograph score. This sketch has no relationship to other scores so it is assumed that it is an early attempt which was discarded. Incomplete.
  - Opus 51 Verzweiflung, December 4, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 123)
    Holograph score. Earliest sketch, parts are not filled out, German words only. Title later appears as Call to charon. Pencil.
  - Opus 51 Verzweiflung, December 4, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 124)
    Holograph score. English words added in pencil.
  - Opus 86 A legend (Box 8, Folder 225)
    Page one appears last. Bound in green paper cover with gamble hinge. Part 1 only.
    - Opus 86 A legend: score (Box 8, Item 225a)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st violin (Box 8, Item 225b)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd violin (Box 8, Item 225c)
    - Opus 86 A legend: viola (Box 8, Item 225d)
    - Opus 86 A legend: cello (Box 8, Item 225e)
    - Opus 86 A legend: bass (Box 8, Item 225f)
    - Opus 86 A legend: Piccolo (Box 8, Item 225g)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st flute (Box 8, Item 225h)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd flute (Box 8, Item 225i)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st oboe (Box 8, Item 225j)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd oboe (Box 8, Item 225k)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st clarinet (Box 8, Item 225l)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd clarinet (Box 8, Item 225m)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st bassoon (Box 8, Item 225n)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd bassoon (Box 8, Item 225o)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st horn (Box 8, Item 225p)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd horn (Box 8, Item 225q)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 3rd horn (Box 8, Item 225r)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 4th horn (Box 8, Item 225s)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st trumpet (Box 8, Item 225t)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd trumpet (Box 8, Item 225u)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 1st trombone (Box 8, Item 225v)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 2nd trombone (Box 8, Item 225w)
    - Opus 86 A legend: 3rd trombone (Box 8, Item 225x)
    - Opus 86 A legend: tuba (Box 8, Item 225y)
    - Opus 86 A legend: tympani (Box 8, Item 225z)
    - Opus 86 A legend: cymbals (Box 8, Item 225aa)
    - Opus 86 A legend: snare drum (Box 8, Item 225bb)
  - Opus 51 Verzweiflung (Box 10, Folder 125)
    Manuscript. Orchestra parts.
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st violin (Box 10, Item 125a)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 2nd violin (Box 10, Item 125b)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: viola (Box 10, Item 125c)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: cello (Box 10, Item 125d)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: bass (Box 10, Item 125e)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st and 2nd horn (Box 10, Item 125f)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 3rd horn (Box 10, Item 125g)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: piccolo (Box 10, Item 125h)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st flute (Box 10, Item 125i)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 2nd flute (Box 10, Item 125j)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st oboe (Box 10, Item 125k)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 2nd oboe (Box 10, Item 125t)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st clarinet (Box 10, Item 125m)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 2nd clarinet (Box 10, Item 125n)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st bassoon (Box 10, Item 125o)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 2nd bassoon (Box 10, Item 125p)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st and 2nd trumpet (Box 10, Item 125q)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 1st trombone (Box 10, Item 125r)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: 2nd trombone (Box 10, Item 125s)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung: tympani (Box 10, Item 125t)
  - Opus 51 Verzweiflung, December 31, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 127)
    Holograph orchestra score. 27 pages. Two typewritten pages found in this copy contain a poem "At Cheron's Ferry." some words are changed and others are substituted in pencil.
  - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra (Box 10, Folder 129)
    Holograph score. Early pencil sketch of the first movement
  - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra (Box 10, Folder 130)
    Holograph score and parts. Pencil sketch of finale
  - Opus 52 Romanza no. 2, November 24, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 131)
    Holograph score. This is a much earlier work which was later expanded into a concerto. Romanza is then the second movement.
    - Opus 52 Romanza no. 2: score, November 24, 1898 (Box 10, Item 131a)
    - Opus 52 Romanza no. 2: violin (Box 10, Item 131b)
  - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: score, 1904 (Box 10, Item 133a)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: violin (Box 10, Item 133b)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra (Box 10, Folder 134)
      Holograph score. Pencil score with all three movements present.
  - Opus 52 Romanza no. 2 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    This is the same as item 131 without the part
  - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra, July - August, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 135)
    Holograph score. Violin and Orchestra. bound with heavy paper cover.
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: score (Box 10, Item 135a)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: soprano violin (Box 10, Item 135b)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st violin (Box 10, Item 135c)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 2nd violin (Box 10, Item 135d)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: viola (Box 10, Item 135e)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: cello (Box 10, Item 135f)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: bass (Box 10, Item 135g)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st flute (Box 10, Item 135h)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 2nd flute (Box 10, Item 135i)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st oboe (Box 10, Item 135j)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 2nd oboe (Box 10, Item 135k)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st and 2nd clarinet (Box 10, Item 135l)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st bassoon (Box 10, Item 135m)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 2nd bassoon (Box 10, Item 135n)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st horn (Box 10, Item 135o)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 2nd horn (Box 10, Item 135p)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 3rd horn (Box 10, Item 135g)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 4th horn (Box 10, Item 135r)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st and 2nd trumpet (Box 10, Item 135s)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 1st trombone (Box 10, Item 135t)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 2nd trombone (Box 10, Item 135u)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: 3rd trombone (Box 10, Item 135v)
    - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra: tympani (Box 10, Item 135w)
  - Opus 52 Concerto for violin and orchestra (Box 10, Folder 136)
    Holograph score. pages 20, 21 and 38 only.
  - Opus 53 no. 7 Sterne uberall and Prelude (Antique) (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Prelude (Antique), March 10, 1889 (Box 10, Item 137b)
      Holograph score. crossed out is Opus 53 no. 4, so this was probably discarded in favor of a song.
    - Opus 53 no. 7 Sterne uberall, June 4, 1899 (Box 10, Item 137a)
      Holograph score. Voice and piano. pencil sketch.
  - Opus 53 no. 9 Nights of music, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 138)
    Holograph manuscript. Marked as new version. Page 4 has a fragment of another song not identified.
  - Opus 53 no. 5 Prelude, March 19, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 139)
    Holograph score. Not included in the revised version.
  - Opus 54 no. 1 Fruhling (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - Opus 54 no. 3 Waldhornklange (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - Opus 54 no. 4 Was die Sonne gluht and Opus 54 no. 6 Im Walde (Box 10, Folder 143)
    - Opus 54 no. 6 Im Walde (Box 10, Item 143b)
    - Opus 54 no. 4 Was die Sonne gluht (Box 10, Item 143a)
  - Opus 54 no. 8 Jagerlied, August 6, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 144)
  - Opus 54 Buch der Liebe (Box 10, Folder 145)
    Holograph score. A group of nine verses by Hoffman von Fallersleben separated by either fermati or short piano interludes. It is not known from the material at hand if this was published as the opus 54 or the items 141-144.
  - Opus 54 Buch der Liebe, June 24, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 146)
    voice and piano holograph score. The same as item 145 except for a part called second prelude which appears before the last verse.
  - Opus 56 Te Deum (Box 10, Folder 149)
    Holograph correction sheet. These corrections were probably sent to the printer for insertion in the score. Accompanied by another scrap of MS paper with several more.
  - Opus 58 no. 5 Christ is our cornerstone (Box 11, Folder 157)
    Holograph score. solo, chorus, and organ. incomplete, first 22 measures.
  - Opus 59 At twilight (Box 11, Folder 158)
    Holograph orchestra score. Inside cover page lists the first performance as October 23, 1903, with Walter Damrosch as conductor. The score is revised with many erasures and corrections.: Some parts include previous version on reverse side.
    - Opus 59 At twilight: score (Box 11, Item 158a)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st violin (Box 11, Item 158b)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd violin (Box 11, Item 158c)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: viola (Box 11, Item 158d)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: cello (Box 11, Item 158e)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: bass (Box 11, Item 158f)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st flute (Box 11, Item 158g)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd flute (Box 11, Item 158h)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st oboe (Box 11, Item 158i)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd oboe (Box 11, Item 158j)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st clarinet (Box 11, Item 158k)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd clarinet (Box 11, Item 158l)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st bassoon (Box 11, Item 158m)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd bassoon (Box 11, Item 158n)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st horn (Box 11, Item 158o)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd horn (Box 11, Item 158p)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 3rd and 4th horn (Box 11, Item 158q)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: trumpet (Box 11, Item 158r)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st trombone (Box 11, Item 158s)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd trombone (Box 11, Item 158t)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 3rd trombone (Box 11, Item 158u)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: tympani (Box 11, Item 158v)
  - Opus 59 At twilight (Box 11, Folder 159)
    Holograph score. Orchestra. Revised score with some erasures and pencil additions. Page 1 has a sheet of paper pasted to the upper half with a poem by Norman Foerster, the composer's son.
    - Opus 59 At twilight: score (Box 11, Item 159a)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd flute (Box 11, Item 159b)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd oboe (Box 11, Item 159c)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd bassoon (Box 11, Item 159d)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd clarinet (Box 11, Item 159e)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd horn (Box 11, Item 159f)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 3rd and 4th horn (Box 11, Item 159g)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: trumpet (Box 11, Item 159h)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd trombone (Box 11, Item 159i)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 3rd trombone (Box 11, Item 159j)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st violin (Box 11, Item 159k)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd violin (Box 11, Item 159l)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: viola (Box 11, Item 159m)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: cello (Box 11, Item 159n)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: bass (Box 11, Item 159o)
  - Opus 59 At twilight (Box 11, Folder 160)
    Holograph score and band parts. Piano score with notes for band arrangement.
    - Opus 59 At twilight: score (Box 11, Item 160a)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: Piccolo (Box 11, Item 160b)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd flute (Box 11, Item 160c)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd oboe (Box 11, Item 160d)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st clarinet (Box 11, Item 160e)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd clarinet (Box 11, Item 160f)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 3rd clarinet (Box 11, Item 160g)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: E-flat clarinet (Box 11, Item 160h)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: bass clarinet (Box 11, Item 160i)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd bassoon (Box 11, Item 160j)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: contra bassoon (Box 11, Item 160k)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd horn (Box 11, Item 160l)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 3rd and 4th horn (Box 11, Item 160m)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st trumpet (Box 11, Item 160n)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd trumpet (Box 11, Item 160o)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: soprano cornet (Box 11, Item 160p)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st cornet (Box 11, Item 160q)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd trombone (Box 11, Item 160r)